# JOE BELMONTE

- www.josephbelmonte.com
- **\** 781-858-3236
- **♀** 35 School Street Milton, MA 02186
- in joe-belmonte
- (?) joebelmonte

#### **Skills**

JavaScript

**HTML** 

CSS

Bootstrap

Node

Ruby

Rails

Ember

Git / GitHub

Handlebars

Heroku

### **Projects**

State Trotter
Bucket List by US
State

Movie Night Personal Movie Database

Tic Tac Toe Simple Tic Tac Toe Game

#### **Summary**

I want to pursue my love of technology and great software by combining the skills I developed over 15 years in market research for the financial services sector – including a high level of attention to detail, and the ability to excel in a fast-paced, deadline-driven environment - with the coding skills I've learned at General Assembly.

#### **Experience**

# General Assembly

**Boston** 

Web Development Immersive

Mar 2017 to lun 2017

- Attended a rigorous 3 month coding boot camp focused on full-stack web development.
- Designed and built several full-stack single-page web applications using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript for front end and Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, and MongoDB for back end.
- Worked in teams and individually using Agile methodology and Git/GitHub for version control.

#### Market Metrics

Boston, MA

Director of Global Research

May 2015 to Mar 2017

Responsible for all survey-based research conducted in the U.S. and Europe, including:

- Ensuring timely and accurate completion and delivery of survey results for over 20 yearly studies requiring roughly 30,000 interviews per year
- Managing a team of roughly 25 Analysts, Associates, and Associate Directors working within the group

## **Director of Operations**

Sep 2011 to May 2015

Responsible for the internal operations for all of Market Metrics via direct or indirect management of a team of roughly 35 employees, including:

- Internal Management, Resource Allocations
- Professional Development, Promotions, and Compensation
- Recruiting and New Hire Training

#### Associate

Jan 2007 to Sep 2011

- Led development of a completely new syndicated research study that examined satisfaction and productivity of field and internal wholesalers for Asset Management and Insurance Companies.
- Managed all phases of the Life Insurance syndicated research cycle, from survey design to analysis of results.
- Led the launch of Market Metrics' first research outside of the U.S

### **Education**

# Dartmouth College

BA Economics and History 2002

GPA: 3.6. Coursework included Microeconomics, Macroeconomics, Statistics, Econometrics, Financial Markets and Institutions, International Trade; US History and foreign relations.